Ana Bogatinovska

+38972207429 bogatinovska.ana@gmail.com anabogatinovska.com

Ana Bogatinovska - CV

ABOUT ME

I enrolled at the Faculty of Computer Science and Engineering at Skopje in 2012 and after two years of struggling, I finally faced the fact that I was never good with institutional education. So I dropped out and started working as a VFX Artist at FX3X. However, 4 years later I lost my VFX Artist job due to a massive lay-off in the company. This was the moment I realized it's time for me to get back to doing what I really liked during my two years at university - Web Design. Since March 2020 I have been actively learning all about web design, web development, frontend and backend development, databases and APIs. Gradually I expanded my knowledge by gaining hands-on experience on different web projects and taking online web development courses. Keep on reading to learn about my journey as a Software Developer. This is my story:

SKILLS

Programming Languages & Framework

Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, Vue, Quasar Framework

Storage

MongoDb, LocalStorage, Vuex store

EXPERIENCE

FX3X - Skopje, North Macedonia— Vfx Roto Artist

August 2015 - May 2020

- Roto animation of movie footage from a given deadline.
- Proficiency in team work.
- Successful completion of the work within a given deadline.

Musala Soft - Skopje, North Macedonia— Junior Software Engineer

April 2021 - present

- Implement demo projects for learning purposes.
- Involved in a project for developing FloorPlan.

MY STORY

- Stopanska banka AD Skopje Homepage A week after watching a few Pluralsight courses about HTML & CSS I felt ready to take on my first real HTML & CSS challenge. For this exercise I decided to clone the design of the home page of one of the best Macedonian Bank's websites. My first attempt was quite good but soon after I started adapting the web page layout in order to make it responsive for smaller device screens I got into trouble. The layout started breaking and the code was too complex. This is when a senior web developer suggested that I read about Mobile First Design. After educating myself about this approach, I started from scratch. This second attempt was a complete success and it took me half the time to reimplement it all over again with the added responsiveness.
- <u>Facebook Home Page</u> Having my confidence boosted by my first HTML & CSS project ever, I decided to take upon another challenge and clone the home page of Facebook. This project was also very good exercise for me because the layout is divided in 4-columns and is completely different from what I did in the previous project.
- Minesweeper Game Soon after finishing my second project I decided I am ready to go to the next level and learn Javascript. After a few Pluralsight courses I set out to test what I had learned by challenging myself to build a Minesweeper game. The first version of the javascript code did what it was supposed to do for the game to work. But the code was awful. Even I couldn't navigate through it myself after a few days away from it. I googled for ways to refactor the code and that's when I was introduced to OOP (Object-Oriented Programming). I successfully refactored the plain javascript code into an OOP version.
- <u>Transverzalec Admin Section</u> This was my first project ever that I built for a client. My role was building the frontend application for the Admin section of <u>pdtransverzalec.org.mk</u> In this project I learned about client server communication, ajax http requests and consuming backend REST APIs. I also learned how Authentication works by implementing JWT-based authentication, centralized state

- management by implementing vuex store and application routing by implementing the vue router. Another important concept which I learned about and implemented was form validations and form submission. Successfully completing this project was a real joy for me.
- APVI (American Passport & Visa International) APVI is an American company for which I completely recreated their old company website. I was provided with visual mockups of the new design which I then implemented in HTML & CSS using the Quasar Framework As part of the website I created the Checkout pages for creating orders and also implemented Authorize.NET Payment Processing. The API of the application was built by another developer and I was provided with a Swagger documentation which I used for learning how to consume the API.
- Full-stack E-Commerce Application After working on the APVI frontend I became very comfortable with consuming APIs and became curious to learn how to do it myself. Since I already knew javascript for the frontend I decided to use that knowledge to start my journey as a full-stack developer. So I came up with a simple e-commerce web app for which I built the Vue frontend, Node backend and MongoDb database. The application features JWt Authentication, User types such as Admin and Regular user, Role-based authorization, Photo upload. Admins can create their own products and regular users can scroll through all active products from all Admins. Then they can add products to their own Shopping Cart.
- Personal Budget Planner This is another full-stack application that I developed for learning purposes. The focus is on the development of a Personal financial management system. Its major features and functionalities are managing monthly finances and expenses. The architecture of the system includes backend modules implemented with Node.js using MySQL database and frontend layer developed in Angular 12. The goal of the project is to allow the user to keep track of personal financial state.

EDUCATION

High School 'Pance Arsovski' - Skopje, North Macedonia

September 2008 - June 2012, Skopje

Online course for Frontend Web Developer - Skopje, North Macedonia

October 2020 - December 2020, FINKI - Skopje

WEB PRESENCE

<u>LinkedIn</u>

<u>GitHub</u>

<u>Portfolio</u>